# **Padraic Kavanagh**

# 174 Maher Road, Graiguecullen, Co.Carlow

Moblie: 089 2472115 Email: padraickavanagh@yahoo.ie

### **Personal Profile:**

Having worked in the Retail industry over the past 10yrs, I have gained a working knowledge of the Retail environment and possess skills such as effective communication and people skills. I have also gained experience working as a Team Leader.

### Skills:

Self motivatedQuick learnerExcellent team playerComputer literate

- Leadership - Creative

### **Employment History:**

### General Assistant. Oct 2016-Aug 2017

## Tesco Carlow, Fairgreen Shopping Centre, Carlow, Co. Carlow.

My main role in Tesco Carlow was being part of a small team left to manage and maintain the off-licene department. The role invovled having good relationship with my two co-workers but the vast majority of the time left to run the department and working on my own. My roles involved managing deliveries, dealing with sales reps and customers and also security jobs. I was also expected to jump into any department that needed help so I was trained in most roles in the shop including checkouts, grocery, backstores and the fresh department. My only christmas in Tesco Carlow I spent my time in the off-licence department our team won employee of the month. In that month of December our sales were over half million euros in our department alone. I was also first aider, fire warden and shop steward in my time there.

# Team Leader/General Assistant. April 2008-Oct 2016 Tesco Tullow,Bunclody Road,Tullow,Co.Carlow.

In Tesco Tullow I spent half my time as a general assistant and a half as a team leader. My team leader role was 75% of my time I was general assistant and 25% of my time as an assistant manager role for my department which included doing rosters, taking care of department weekly updates and the training of the people in my department. I spent time in all departments in my time in Tesco Tullow. I was a trained first aider , fire warden and elected shop steward for the 8 years I was there.

### Apprentice Plumber. Sep 2005-Feb 2008

## Monastery Merchants, Chapel Lane, Tullow, Co. Carlow.

During my time as an apprentice plumber I got a great understanding of construction. I learned alot of problem solving skills, how important team work is, time keeping and achieving targets and deadlines. I also had to use my own inicitave and work on my own.

# Mandate Trade Union Shop Steward. Jun 2008-Aug 2017 Tesco Tullow/Carlow

Tesco was a company who when you were employed with them you had to join a trade union. Most employees are members of Mandate Trade Union. I was elected as a shop steward and union representive by my co-workers. I stayed in this role for all of my time in the company. This role included being a bridge between staff and management, dealing with greivences from staff and communicating with management. I learned a great deal about employment law and rights. I also learned negotition skills and organisation skills. In this role I built trust with my co-workers and management.

## Chairman/Co-founder Carlow Singles Darts League 2015-Present

One of my past times is darts. In 2015 myself and a few other people started an annual two month long county wide dart tournament. I was elected chairman of a committee of eight people. In this role I had to organise suitable venues and get funding to run the tournament. We are currently in our fourth year of the tournament and it has been a great success. 60+ people play in it every year. We have a prizepool of over €2000. We play in four venues and that is where we are funded from. We are trying to get more sponsorship this year. We added a youth tournament last year. Numbers for the tournament are growing every year. It is very challenging to deal with fixtures, venues, prizepools and players for the tournament but I am proud of what we have created which is the biggest annual darts tournament in carlow and surrounding areas.

## **Education:**

Carlow IT. Currently Attending Certificate in Digital Media.

2002-2004 Leaving Certificate Tullow Community School, Tullow, Co. Carlow Irish - C1 Ordinary level English - B2 Ordinary level Maths - B2 Ordinary level French - C3 Ordinary level Tech Drawing - D1 Higher level Engineering - D1 Ordinary level Construction Studies - C3 Ordinary level

References available on request.